TEJ PRASAD SUBEDI

304-666 Ontario Street, Toronto ON M4X 1N1 Phone: 647-334-8509 Email: tejsubedi@gmail.com | GitHub: https://github.com/tejsubedi LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tejsubedi/ Portfolio: https://portfoliotejsubedi.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Results driven, full stack developer with a background in information technology for 10 years. A self-motivated, ambitious and dedicated Individual, with proven comprehension of full stack applications. Dedicated to building interactive and user-centered website designs. Excellent written and oral communication skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, C#, Java, Python, PHP

Scripting Languages: JavaScript RDBMS/DBMS: MySQL, Mongo DB

Libraries and Frameworks: ASP.NET, jQuery, ReactJS, Sequelize, and Express

Server Environment: Node.js

Collaborative Tools: GitHub, Agile Methods

PROJECTS

Event Hunter

GitHub: https://github.com/bootcampcoder/project-1 **Deployment**: https://bootcampcoder.github.io/project-1/

- **About**: This application is about to find free events within 10km of user's location by implementing event application.
- Role: plugin Google maps application with the location searching of events.
- **Technologies:** JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase Authentication, materialize, bootstrap, html, moment.js and Google Maps.

Zombie Blasters

GitHub: https://github.com/Esther12/The-Wall

Deployment: https://zombie-blasters.herokuapp.com/

- About: It implements a shooting game. If you shoot a civilian, you will lose a life.
- **Role**: create Sequelize-ORM query model and login-signup page with implementing passport authentication and bcrypt.js.
- **Technologies**: JavaScript, jQuery, GreenSock-JS, Node.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Passport, bcrypt.js, CSS, HTML, session.

Link to Lift

GitHub: https://github.com/Indian-Indepth/link-to-lift **Deployment:** https://link-to-lift.herokuapp.com/

- About: Provide personal training via connecting to the favorite trainer.
- **Role**: create payment method and generate html pdf as backend developer and integrated backend code with frontend.
- **Technologies**: JavaScript, ReactJS, Google Authentication, Bulma, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Braintree payments platform, html-pdf.

Tej Prasad Subedi

WORK HISTORY

Freelance Software Developer

Smart Online Solution, Kathmandu, Nepal

2018 – present

Designed and implemented web interfaces for Rostro Menu application using ASP.NET, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, C# and MySQL.

Key Accomplishments:

- Designed and implemented a .NET interface for the online registering platform.
- Plugin google map application with the location searching of the restaurant.
- Designed and implemented user friendly Android interface.
- Learned various technical background and in-depth understanding of various technologies i.e. ETL, Content management, Web application development and deployment.

Freelance Software Developer

Web Tech, Kathmandu, Nepal.

2014 - 2017

Designing of web interfaces using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.

Key Accomplishments:

- Experience with creating and managing project documentations and deliverables including schedules, issue, action and relocation of projects.
- Learned to maintain a positive attitude while on the job.
- Managed large scale projects from initial planning and development.

Database Administrator

Al Safeer Group of Companies, Sharjah, UAE

2009 - 2013

Formulated of internal inventory controls, policy to comply, install and maintain the performance of database servers implementing the command of SQL and SQL server tools.

Key Accomplishments:

- Learned to provide insight and robust solutions to support the database process and optimizing database security through various access control.
- Works with the business to ensure compliance and effective control of database security, backup and recovery.
- Learned various tools of web technology JAVA, HTML and CSS with the web development team and implement of SQL database.

Senior Account Manager

Pioneer Plastic Factory L.L.C. Umm Al Quwain, UAE

2007 - 2008

Prepared and recorded asset, liability, revenue, and expenses.

Key Accomplishments:

- Learned database management with introducing Oracle database system.
- Maintain effectively to solve the inventory accuracy through data analysis.
- Good command in to use Microsoft office, Word, Excel and accounting software Tally.

Tej Prasad Subedi 3

EDUCATION

UofT SCS Coding Boot Camp

UofT School of Continuing Studies, Toronto, ON, Canada 2019 - 2019 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Computer Programmer Analyst

George Brown College, Toronto, ON, Canada

2016 - 2019

A 3 years' intensive program focused on gaining technical programming and software designing skills with emphasis on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, C#, .NET, Java, Python, Angular, ReactJS, Agile methodologies and so on.

Bachelor's Degree in Business Management

Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal

1999 - 2002

A 3 years' intensive program focused on business, economics, accounting and finance.